グルル
Hey, Eruruu!
おお エルルゥ
Nuwangi...
ヌワンギ
So you're here too, huh?
ちっ テメエも一緒か
Listen, Eruruu, I'm not here today
just to shoot the breeze.
エルルゥ 今日はな
遊びに来た訳じゃないんだ
Because last night a thief
broke into the mansion!
昨日 屋敷に賊が侵入した！
And we know you villagers are
giving shelter to him!
この村の連中が
匿っていることは分かってんだ
We won't stand for it!
隠してると承知しねえぞ
ニャハプププププ
And thus you come down on us in force!
大勢で押し寄せよってからに
Old bag!
ばばあ
ウプフ　トゥスクル 久しいにゃもね
Long time no see, Tuskuru!
I may not look it, but I'm
actually quite busy,
こう見えても忙しいんだ
so I've no time to be bothered
with the likes of you.
お前らにかまってる暇なんぞ無いね
う ばばあ
You old bag!
I don't recall raising such
a foul-mouthed kid!
そんな口を利く子に育てた覚えは無いよ
ぐううっ
I must say I really owe you
one there, Tuskuru!
トゥスクル お前にゃ随分
世話になっとったし
ふん 痔の薬は効いとるかえ？
So has that hemorrhoid medication
been working for you?
In trying to sympathize with these beggars,
貧乏人連中の気持ちも汲んでやって
いろいろと大目に見てやっとったにゃもが
there are a lot of things I have
graciously overlooked.
But you have overstepped your bounds!
調子に乗りすぎにゃも
Seize this old lady!
このばあさんをひっ捕らえな
Grandma!
おばあちゃん
kodomo no goro no yume wa
The dream I had when I was a child,
子供の頃の夢は　色褪せない落書きで
iroase nai rakugaki de
were drawn to my heart's desire
omou mama kaki suberasete
with scribbles that wouldn't fade away
思うまま書き滑らせて
描く未来へとつながる
egaku mirai he to tsunagaru
and are connected to the future i draw.
Utawarerumono
sumiwataru sora
The clear skies
澄み渡る空　果てしないほど青く
hateshinai hodo aoku
were endlessly blue.
mujaki na kokoro ni
And my innocent heart,
無邪気な心に　充たされ魅かれてく
mitasare hikareteku
being satisfied, was attracted to them.
yagate jiyuu ni tobimawareru
I finally obtained wings
やがて自由に飛びまわれる
翼(はね)を手に入れて
hane wo teni irete
with which I could fly freely.
muku na hitomi wa motometeku
I want to go to the end of the skies
無垢な瞳は求めてく
空の向こうへ　行きたいな
sora no mukou he ikitai na
which my pure eyes desire.
kore tonai negai kara
If one wish could be granted
止め処ない願いから　一つだけ叶うのなら
hitotsu dake kanau no nara
out of countless others...
dare ni mo yuzuri taku wa nai
I feel that it should be to grab onto a dream
誰にも譲りたくはない
夢を掴みたいと思うよ
yume wo tsukamitai to omou yo
and never be tempted to let go.
kodomo no goro no yume wa
The dreams I had when I was a child,
子供の頃の夢は　色褪せない落書きで
iroase nai rakugaki de
were drawn eternally,
itsuwademo kaki tsuzukerareta
with scribbles that wouldn't fade away
いつまでも描き続けられた
願う未来へとつながる
negau mirai he to tsunagaru
and are connected to the future I wish for.
One-Way Path
Chief!
村長
Grandma!
おばあちゃん
Eruruu!
エルルゥ
But!
でも
プププププ　いい気味にゃも
That'll teach you!
ふん
I imagine the dungeons will seem pretty
cold to an elderly woman!
年寄りの身にゃ
地下牢は冷たいだろにゃもね
How can you people do such a thing?
お前たち こんなことをして
ドュフフフフ…
Who threw that stone just now!?
誰だ　今 石を投げた奴は
ミャー ウー
Aruruu!
アルルゥ
Why, you little brat!
にゃも　このガキ
Let go of my grandma!
おばあちゃんを放せ
ミャー ミャー
うっ どおっ おおい
どおおっ
う？　お ああ おい
落ち…
ええいっ
Mukkuru!
ムックル
Don't toy with us!
舐めやがって
Stop!
よせ
えいやっ
おばあちゃん
Grandma?
大丈夫かえ？
Are you all right?
Grandma!
おばあちゃん
くっ 貴様ら
You bastards!
He acted on his own!
そ そいつが勝手に
ミャーッ
Hey, I don't know anything!
にゃ にゃ にゃも　何も知らないにゃも
Get us outta here!
だ だ 出せーっ
ギャオーッ
くうっ
Grandma... Grandma!
おばあちゃん おばあちゃん
Hang in there!
しっかり
ギャオーッ
Grandma, Grandma!
おばあちゃん おばあちゃん
I'll have this medicine ready for
you right away, Grandma!
おばあちゃん すぐにお薬が出来るから
Here now, just leave this to Eruruu.
ほら ここはエルルゥに任せて
But!
だけど
Come on, now.
仕方ない
If anything happens, let me know right away.
あんちゃん 何かあったらすぐに
I will.
はい
Here you go, Grandma. Drink this.
おばあちゃん これ
飲んで
Oh, it doesn't matter now...
いや
もうええ
This is my body. I already know it's
not going to pull through.
自分の体じゃ
もう助からんくらい よく分かっとる
Don't talk like that!
そんなこと言わないで
Here now, let me get a better
look at the two of you.
さあ２人とも
もっとよく顔を見せとくれ
Grandma...
おばあちゃん
Ah, you're so adorable...
ああ 可愛いのう
I'm so proud of my two granddaughters.
２人とも わしの自慢の孫じゃ
A wound like this should
heal up right away!
そんな怪我 すぐに治るから
ほう
You're getting to look so much more
like my older sister, Eruruu.
エルルゥはますます
姉様そっくりになっていくのう
Just like my older sister,
who was so beautiful and kind.
美しくて とても優しかった姉様に
Grandma?
おばあちゃん
Eruruu was the name of my older
sister, whom I loved so.
エルルゥという名は
大好きだった姉様の名前
ああ　それじゃあ
Then, that story you'd often tell me was...
おばあちゃんが
よく聞かせてくれたお話って
Yes, you were named after my older sister.
お前の名前は 姉様からいただいたんだよ
And Aruruu, you look exactly
like I did when I was little.
アルルゥや
お前はわしの小さな頃そっくりじゃ
フフ 今じゃ想像つかんかもしれんがの
Though you may not be able
to imagine it now,
people used to fawn over me and
tell me how adorable I was.
あの頃は可愛い可愛いと
よく可愛がられたもんじゃ
Grandma...
おばあちゃん
Listen now, you two always be
good to one another.
いいかえ ２人とも仲良くな
It's fine if you argue or fight
every now and then,
時には言い争うのもええ
喧嘩するのもええ
but in all the world the only sisters
you have are each other.
じゃが
お前たちはこの世で
たった２人きりの姉妹
No matter what happens,
you two work together,
どんなことがあっても
２人で力を合わせて
いつまでも仲良く な
and always be good to one another.
Hakuoro...
ハクオロや
Yes?
はい
Would you hear an old fool's last request?
最後に
最後に この老いぼれの頼みを
聞いてもらえんか
I would.
はい
I have lived a long life,
more than long enough.
わしはもう 十分すぎるほど長く生きた
I have no reluctance over
setting off on this new journey.
これからの旅立ちに 何のためらいも無い
But I am concerned about these two.
じゃが 気掛かりなのはこの子たちのこと
I beg you, please stay by their sides.
お願いじゃ
この子たちの側に居てやっておくれ
I will.
はい
Grandma! I don't want to go on without you!
おばあちゃん
おばあちゃんも一緒じゃなきゃ嫌
Eruruu...
エルルゥ
おばあちゃん
Grandma...
Grandma!
おばあちゃん
I can die in peace with such lovely
granddaughters caring for me.
可愛い孫たちに看取られて逝ける
I have truly lived a good life.
わしの人生 満更では無かった
Yes.
はい
I have no regrets.
何も思い残すことは無い
None, none at... all...
何も 何も
Grandma...
おばあ ちゃん？
おばあちゃん
Grandma?
Grandma!
おばあちゃん？　おばあちゃん？
Grandma! Grandma!
おばあちゃん　はあ はあ　おばあちゃん
Grandma!
おばあちゃん
Grandma...
Grandma!
おばあちゃん
What did you say!?
何だと？
Say it again!
もう一度言ってみろ
Tuskuru-san has died.
トゥスクルさんは 逝かれた
She passed away just earlier.
たった今 旅立たれたところだ
When you were right there with her!?
あんたが居ながら
なぜだ
Why!?
Why couldn't you protect her!?
なぜ守れなかった
Damn it...
ちくしょう
Damn it! Damn it!
ちくしょう　ちくしょう
This is because I failed.
俺が しくじったから
That is not it.
違う
You need to think of what lies ahead now.
これからのことを考えるんだ
Oboro?
オボロ？
Tuskuru-sama was virtually a parent to us.
トゥスクル様は俺たちにとって
I'm not nice enough to be able to stand
silently by when my parent is killed.
親も同然の方だった
俺は親を殺されて黙っていられるほど
お人好しではない
Do you think Tuskuru-san would be glad
to hear you talking like that?
そんなこと
トゥスクルさんが
喜ぶとでも思っているのか？
She would probably never stand for it,
決して許さないだろうな
but even so, I still can't forgive them.
それでも 俺は奴らを許さん
We'll go with you, my lord!
若様 僕たちも
No! This is something that
I've brought down on us.
駄目だ
これは俺が招いてしまったことだ
But, my lord!
若様
I have a favor to ask of you.
あんたに頼みがある
Take care of these two and Yuzuha.
こいつらと
ユズハを頼む
Wait!
待て
All else aside, you are the one
who made Yuzuha smile.
あんたは 何よりユズハに微笑みをくれた
It made me dislike you so much
that I felt like killing you.
そんなあんたを
殺したいほど疎ましくも思った
The thing is...
だがな
Though I hate to admit it,
I was actually drawn to you.
認めたくはないが
惹かれてもいたんだ
Oboro...
オボロ
You're the only one whom I could
ask such a thing of.
こんなことを頼めるのは
あんたしか居ない
Then there is no changing
your mind about this?
どうしても行くつもりか？
This is something I have to deal with.
俺の けじめだ
ふわ ああああああ
Thief!
ぞ 賊だーっ
でやーっ
でやっ
うがああっ
ずあっ
でやーっ
This guy's strong!
こいつ
強い
What's the matter!?
どうした　ここの兵は
俺１人止められないのか
Can't you soldiers stop just me on my own?
Engage the enemy!
出合えーっ
Bastard! Are you Nuwangi?
貴様が ヌワンギか
Who the hell are you!?
な 何だテメエ
I don't have any name to give
to you, you bastard.
貴様に名乗る名など無い
でやーっ
Dad!
親父
So is this the little rat that snuck in here?
忍び込んだネズミというのは
そいつにゃもか？
I guess you could say the tables
have turned! Don't ya think!?
形勢逆転ってやつだな
Sasante! This saves me the
time of searching for you.
ササンテ
探す手間が省けたぞ
プヒヒヒ　若いいい体をしている
Young and in great shape...
Looks like I won't be getting bored tonight!
今夜から退屈せずに済みそうにゃもよ
Don't you screw with me!
舐めるなあ
でやーっ
ええいっ
Let go!
放せ
A youngster like you...
おみゃあごとき若造が
Did you actually think you could beat
the wisest, most refined,
この国で最も賢く優雅で
気高く強い武士のにゃもに
most noble and strongest man
in all the land?
勝てるとでも思ったにゃも？
Don't you mean the slab of meat
with the strongest odor?
臭みの強い 肉の間違いじゃないのか？
プフー
The rat has a big mouth.
口の減らないネズミにゃもよ
ジュルル ジュル
Listen, Kid...
あんちゃん
Tuskuru-sama has entrusted
everything to you.
トゥスクル様は
あんちゃんに全てを託した
So that means you are our
village chief from now on.
なら これからは
あんちゃんが村長ってことだ
But I am not...
自分には
Please, tell us what we're going to do now!
さあ 言ってくれ
これからどうするのかを
We'll follow your lead.
俺たちゃ あんちゃんに付いてく
Forget it. I could not possibly
be your village chief.
駄目だ
自分には村長なんて無理だ
No, there's no one else. The job is yours.
いや 他の誰でもねえ
あんちゃんがやるんだ
But, this...
親父さん
Everyone...
皆
Hakuoro-sama!
ハクオロ様
Hakuoro-sama, we were all drifters.
僕たちはもともと
戦や権力争いで故郷を失ったり
Some of us lost our homes
to war or political strife,
and some of us were persecuted
for things we didn't do.
罪を着せられ追われたり
We have all run away from such
intolerance and bigotry.
そんな辺境にまで
逃げて来た者たちなんです
This is where we ran, and Tuskuru-sama
saved us from dying beggars' deaths.
こんな所まで逃げて 野垂れ死にするところを
トゥスクル様に救ってもらいました
So please, find it in your heart to save...
だからどうか 若様を
To save our lord!
若様を助けてください
Everyone...
皆
Do you all realize what you are about to do?
自分たちが何をしようてしているのか
分かって言ってるのか
There will not be any turning back.
後戻りは出来なくなるんだぞ
ああ 分かってる
Yes, we understand.
Open the storehouse!
蔵を 開けろ
ふんっ
ええいっ　ええいっ
でやーっ
行けーっ
ええい くっ
でえいっ
Outta the way!
ぬうううんっ
ふんっ
What are you doing on the front line, Kid?
You're our general!
あんちゃん 大将が出張ってどうすんだい
There is no turning back for us now.
もう我々は後には引けない
That is exactly why I should take
the lead in this first battle.
なればこそ 初陣は
自分が先頭に立つべきだ
でえい　はっ はっ
でえいっ
You!
貴様
I spare your life and then you go
throwing it away like this.
せっかく助かった命を
粗末に扱うとは
My life doesn't matter.
俺の命など どうでもいい
Do you hear that?
聞こえますか？
It seems that those are your people out there.
どうやらあなたの仲間たちのようです
Those guys...
あいつら
For the moment, things appear
to be going in their favor,
今のところは
上手くいっているようですが
but their ranks number far less than ours.
兵の数が違う
They will soon be overpowered.
すぐに鎮圧されるでしょう
Even if they manage to survive,
they will lose everything.
例え生き延びたとしても
何もかも失う
You have no cause and no flag to stand under.
大義も無く 旗も無い
Why do you fight?
あなたたちは なぜ抗うのです
To live.
生きる ためじゃねえか
In that case, you're better off
living upright under the law.
なれば 法の下に正しく暮らせばいい
Would that be enough to keep our stomachs full?
それで腹が膨れるのか？
Would it keep us from freezing
to death in the cold!?
凍えずに済むのか？
死んでいった家族や仲間を
弔ってやれるのか？
Would it honor the memory of my family
and friends who have died!?
You have the eyes of an animal.
まるで動物の目ですね
General! So this is where you were.
大将
こんな所に居やしたか
Man, I've been looking all over for ya!
いやー 探しましたぜ
Let's go, Kurou.
クロウ 行きましょう
We'll return to the emperor's side at once.
すぐに聖上の下へ戻ります
え？　ここはいいんですかい？
Huh? You want to leave him here like this?
General?
大将
General!
でえやっ
うらっ
Outta the way!
おら どきやがれ
Damn, after we made it so far...
くそ ここまで踏み込んだってのに
You head back, Kid!
あんちゃんは戻れ
Don't be absurd.
バカ言うな
Too late!
遅い
オボロ
You're the one who's been leading them?
あんたが 指揮していたのか？
You are in no shape to fight!
お前 その体
This is nothing compared to the shame
Tuskuru-sama had to endure.
こんなもの トゥスクル様が
受けた辱めに比べれば
My lord!
若様
若様 ご無事で
My lord! You're all right!
So this is the "lord" they
were talking about?
こいつが例の若様か
Dori, Gura, how is Yuzuha?
ドリィ グラァ
ユズハは？
She is resting right now.
はい お休みになられています
I... I see...
そ そうか
My lord!
若様
Don't touch me!
さ 触るな
I'm all right.
俺は 大丈夫だ
Let's go. This way!
行くぞ
こっちだ
おばあちゃん
Grandma...
They'll be all right, Hakuoro-san too.
大丈夫
皆も ハクオロさんも
They'll all come back.
ちゃんと帰ってくる
Sasante!
ササンテ
プヒ？
What are you doing!?
な 何だテメエら
Are you such a fool that you can't comprehend
what's going on right now?
この状況を理解出来ないほど
お前は愚かなのか？
Fool?
愚か？
It... It couldn't be!
な まさか
It is!
そのまさかだ
You guys have done something you
absolutely never should have done!
オメエたちはな
絶対にやっちゃいけないことを
やっちまったんだよ
Are you telling me that
old bag bit the dust!?
あのばばあが
くたばったとでも言うのか？
Don't hand me a line like that.
ハハ　嘘
吐くんじゃねえよ
You'd pull this just for the sake of
a single old woman like her!?
あんなばばあ１人のために
こんなことをしでかしたにゃも？
でやーっ
ひいいいあはっ
Nuwangi! Nuwangi!
ヌワンギ ヌワンギ ヌワンギ
Nuwangi!
I don't know anything!
I don't know anything at all!
知らん　にゃもは何も知らんにゃもー
ふんっ
ぬうっ
You okay, Kid?
あんちゃん？
Hey, Kid!
あんちゃん
What is it, Pops...
親父 さん
It's over.
終わったぜ
You sure it was all right not to
have provided any backup?
加勢しなくて良かったんですかい？
Well, if that's what works for you,
it's certainly fine by me.
ま 大将がそれでいいって言うんなら
かまわないんですがね
ぶはあっ
Why? How did this happen?
何で 何でこんなことに
I never meant for this to happen!
俺はこんなつもりじゃ　はあ
That's it, it's because of him!
そうだ あいつだ
Everything went out of control
after he showed up.
あいつが現れてから 何もかも
It's him! It's all because of him!
あいつだ
あいつのせいだー
Was this the right thing to do?
これで 正しかったのか？
I owe you yet again.
また 借りが出来た
But why? Why did you come?
だがなぜ なぜ来たんだ
あんたたち 何をしたのか
分かっているのか？
Do you realize what you all have done?
Are your wounds okay now?
怪我はもういいのか？
Huh? Well, pretty much.
これぐらい
Then I won't need to hold back.
なら遠慮は要らんな
うがっ
ぐはっ
Do we realize what we have done, you ask?
何をしたか分かってるのかだと？
With what has happened now,
こうなった以上
the imperial court will not waste any time
sending out forces to suppress us.
朝廷はすぐにでも
討伐軍を送り込んでくる
道は２つ
We have two choices, fight or be massacred!
戦うか皆殺しにされるかだ
If you know that, then why did you do this!?
それが分かっていながら なぜ
If I had been the only one to die,
it would have been over and done with!
俺１人が死ねば それで済んだことだ
Do you really mean that?
それは本気で言っているのか？
The one I can forgive least of all
何より
何より許せないのは
is myself for taking advantage
of the situation as I have.
こうしてそれを利用した 自分自身だ
Welcome home.
お帰りなさい
I'm back.
ただいま
Just let me be for a moment...
少し
このままで
Silently it comes, the colorless world
静かに訪れる
色なき世界
すべての時を止め
I stop time and drift off to sleep...
眠りにつく
炎さえも凍てついた
honou sae mo itetsuita
I seek the solitude
孤独の中求む
kokuno naka moto mu
that freezes even flames.
魂から結びつき　私を恋い温めて
tamashi kara musubitsuki
Connecting with your soul,
watashi wo koi atatamete
warm me with your love.
嗚呼　祈りの言葉がふるえ
a inori no kotoba ga furue
Ah...the words of prayer tremble...
嗚呼　弱きいのちが消えても
a yowaki no chika kiete mo
Ah even if the faint-hearted
were to disappear...
くりかえす　輪廻の流れ辿り
kurikaesu innen no nagare tadori
Following the recurring paths of fate.
終わらない世界の宿命を見つめてる
owaranai sekai no shukumei wo mitsumeteru
I gaze upon the never-ending world's destiny.
くりかえし　詠われる者達よ
kurikaeshi utawareru mono tachi yo
Oh the ones being sung continuously
守られてまどろむ宵
mamorarete madoromu you ni
be protected and sleep.
Daughter of the Forest